# Simon Marqvard Jensen

Simonmarqvard@gmail.com +45 27 12 63 82

Scientific researcher in the field of sports medicine. Exploring human biology and exercise through research in muscle tissue, immune cells and stem cells. Interested in using programming languages, data and electronics to explore, access and portray new areas of human physiology, health and movement. International experience from several acknowledged research institutions and sports facilities. Extensive background in communication, teaching and patient care. A smiling, curious, hard working and optimistic human being who thrives in a team-based environment.

- Experienced teacher / communicator.
- Strong programming and coding skills in Java, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
- International research experience. Featured on several original research publications to be released in 2017.
- Extensive background in movement analysis, correction and optimization.
- Speaks Danish, English, German, Norwegian and Swedish. .

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Research Assistant Institute of Sports Medicine Copenhagen, DK

2016 - Present

- Study coordinator in a worldwide investigation conducted by Novartis. A phase III clinical
  trail examining the effects of anti-myostatin in Sarcopenic elderly. I contribute to all
  aspects of the study: recruitment, screening, physical testing, body composition scans,
  blood collections, medicine infusion, electrocardiography etc.
- Featured in a study on macrophages and inflammation in response to muscle damage.
   Assisting on targets of interest, muscle biopsy procedures and preparation of human muscle tissue.
- Featured in a study examining the function of cultured muscle stem cells and fibroblasts in young and elderly women.
- Currently working on the publication of my Masters thesis on immune cells and inflammation.

### Teacher Fitness Institute, DK

2013 - Present

- Course teacher in human anatomy and human physiology. Introducing participants of various professional backgrounds to important concepts of human health, function and training.
- In charge of the e-learning programme. Developer of e-learning instruction videos and supplemental material available to active students.

# Performance specialist EXOS, USA

2012 & 2015

- Two separate learning opportunities with EXOS / Athletes Performance. A world-leading facility in applied research and innovation for human performance.
- Daily movement educator and instructor, involved with numerous professional athletes from all major sports divisions at the EXOS headquarter in Arizona.
- Experience on rehabilitation and corrective exercises at the Mayo Clinic EXOS facility in Minneapolis, to improve physical function in individuals with injuries.

## Research Intern Sportsmedizin Saarbrücken, GE

2011

# • Engaged in a big intervention study at Universität des Saarlandes, Germany, to investigate the effects of different training interventions on untrained individuals. Tasks included: data collection of various blood parameters, tranformation of data into simple user guidelines, heart monitoring during endurance test, etc.

#### Other

2010 - Present

- Participated in an interdisciplinary design project for the Danish architecture center (DAC). Involved in all aspects from design to execution of a landmark at Roskilde Festival 2013. Participants included in this project were selected by a committee - based on submitted ideas.
- External examiner in anatomy and physiology at "Paul Petersens Idrætsinstitut" the first founded sports and gymnastics institute yet to exist in Denmark.

- Lecture on Strength and movement training at the "International Parkour Gathering 2013" at Gerlev.
- Internship at Spectrum Sports Performance in Orlando, FL.

### **EDUCATION**

### Interactive telecommunications program New York university, USA 2017 - 2019

Learning new coding languages, data visualization, physical computing and creative use
of technology. My ambition is to combine this learning with my knowledge from biology.

• Relevant coursework: The API of you, Physical computing, Developing assistive technologies, Creating with web API's, The nature of code.

### Master of Science - Human Physiology The University of Copenhagen, DK 2009 - 2016

- Masters degree in Human Physiology with a bachelors degree in Physical Education.
  Optional courses with emphasis on muscle physiology and neurophysiology. Masters
  thesis on changes in the ageing muscle was awarded with the highest possible
  recognition following a public presentation/defence.
- Relevant coursework: Biomechanics, experimental design and statistics in bio-science, functional neurobiology, biochemistry, human physiology, neuroplasticity, anatomy, physical education in society: today and future concerns, etc.

# Economics major, Granted a full scholarship Rollins College, USA

2007 - 2009

• Economics major and physical education minor. Participated on the men's varsity soccer team. Granted a full athletic scholarship due to a professional background in soccer.